Hello, everyone. Welcome
back to another lesson with us
here at EnglishPod. My name
is Marco and I'm Erica and today
We're going back
to school. That's right.
We're talking about
my least favorite subject
That would be math. That's right. Okay,
so we're gonna be talking about math now
I know that many of you
of course no math right,
but do you know the
operations in English?
Many people find it hard to find the right
words to talk about math in English, right?
So that's what we're gonna be
looking at today and we'll also look at
some names that you can call
people who are really really really smart
So let's listen to our
dialogue for the first time
and then we'll come back
and look at those math words
All right children, let's review Tommy
pay attention. Sorry Miss Catholic
Okay, Crystal now tell
me what's for plus 11
15 Miss Catholic always has crystal.
She's such a teacher's pet
Okay, and what about 56 and minus 60
Negative four very good 12 times 12
very good suck up. What are we for?
Zero divided by one zero.
How did you know that?
Okay, smarty pants
the square root of two
But you're not going to
get that one do it all um
Well, four one four two one three five
All right, so that's one
smart little girl, huh?
Yeah, pretty smart
actually smarter than me
All right, so let's take a look
at some of those words that
the teacher used to ask her
about certain operations in
language takeaway
Language takeaway
Okay, so like we said
you guys know how to do
math and you know the
words in your language
But maybe in English,
it's a little bit harder to
find the right words.
So let's look at those now
Okay, so let's look at the
first question that she asked
What's four plus 11 four plus 11?
Okay, plus plus
All right, so four plus 11 Erica
is let me take a look at here
15 15, okay, so we
are adding right.
Yes, so that's how you would
say let's go with an easy one
Two plus two four four
right or five plus five
Ten ten. Okay.
You're really testing. Nice skills
So that's how you would add numbers now.
What about taking away number day?
So taking away or subtracting. All
right, let's test you again in the dialogue
She said 56 minus 60 56
minus 60 equals negative four
Okay, minus so that's negative right minus
So and of course if you have
56 apples and you take away 60
You are left with negative four negative
four actually you're left with zero apple
Exactly now that answer is also interesting
negative four negative four that means
Minus four right four less than zero or
less than zero very good negative four
Okay, so now for our next operation
12 times 12
12 times 12 12 times 12 now
Marco don't ask me the answer
All right 12 times 12 equals
144 now that's multiplying right
or multiplication multiplication
Okay, so this times
part it's very easy to
remember because for
example four times four
You can just say four the
number four and you add it right
four times four times four
plus four plus four plus four right
So times times uh-huh
now the opposite of times
all right the opposite
of multiplication is
Division division. Okay, so in our dialogue
the teacher said zero divided by one
Zero divided by One zero divided by
one any number divided by zero is zero
All right, so let's give another
example 15 divided by three
All right, so 15 divided
by three equals five five
Exactly so divided by divided by very good
So after division the teacher was
very impressed and now she asked
a very hard mathematical
operation especially for a girl this age
The square root of two the square root of
Square root so let's give some
examples to show what is the square root?
Okay, so if I ask you
the square root of nine
Three three right what
about the square root of
Four two two okay
So now one more the square root of 16 four
Four mm-hmm. Okay, so
you notice the pattern right
and I'm sure everyone knows
this in their own language
How you would get a square root exactly?
So this language um is pretty simple
you all know it in your own language
But let's hear it again in English
one more time with the dialogue
All right children, let's review Tommy
pay attention sorry Miss Cadillac
Okay, Crystal now tell
me what's four plus 11
Miss Cadillac always as
crystal she's such a teacher's pet
Okay, and what about 56 minus 60
Um negative four
Very good 12 times 12 very good suck up 144
Zero divided by one zero
How did you know that?
Okay, smarty pants the square root of two
Bet you're not going to
get that one do it all um
One point four one four two one three five
Okay, so we understand the mathematical
operations that we saw here very easy
But now there was another
little kid in there who was
very I think envious or jealous.
Yeah, Tommy Tommy, right?
So he called her a
couple of different names.
Well, let's look at those
now in fluency builder
Fluency builder
Okay, so the first one that
he called crystal the little girl.
He called her a
teacher's pet teacher's pet
Teachers pet a teacher's pet. So Erica.
What exactly is a teacher's pet?
It is the favorite student
the teacher has in that class.
All right, so it's always a
student that's helping the teacher
Yeah, the smartest students.
Yeah, the teacher's pet.
Yeah, and it has a
negative meaning in English
Yeah, I wouldn't say that
it's a good thing to be
the teacher's pet like the
teacher thinks it's good
Yeah, but all of the
friends and the classmates
they think it's bad. Yeah,
exactly teacher's pet and
Similar to teacher's pet is a suck up
Suck up suck up again
suck up. What what is this?
What is a suck up a suck
up is a person who tries
Really really hard to
make the teacher like him
Okay, now we can also use it outside
of the classroom, right? Yeah at work
Maybe okay. There is always at work. There
is always one person who's the suck up. Yes
Now again, this has a
negative meaning in English.
Yeah, I guess in the workplace
the rest of your colleagues
Don't really like that person
who's considered to be the suck
up who's always trying to
please the boss exactly all right
All right, so the teacher calls crystal a
Smarty pants smarty
pants. Smarty pants.
Okay, so this is also a
little name calling, right?
So what is a smarty pants
somebody who is too
smart too smart who
tries too hard to be
smart now This is
only for little kids, right?
You I wouldn't call you a smarty pants.
No, it's definitely for children adults
Don't say this unless maybe
you are joking or having
fun with someone. Yeah,
but if you say it you are
Suggesting that you're being like a
child right. Yeah. Okay, smarty pants
And our last one and this is also a very
good phrase and a way to describe someone
Know it all know it all
know it all I know it all
Sometimes you say
Mr. Know it all right.
Yeah, that's right. Okay. So what
is a know it all somebody who?
tries to show everyone
that they know it all
they know everything.
Yeah, they're so smart
They have the answers
yeah, but they really really
try and show everyone
that they know everything
These people can be sometimes a little bit
irritating, right? Yeah, very very annoying
Knowing yeah, all right, so it's not a
good thing to be a know it all all the time
Yeah, actually all of these
phrases are not good things to be
Okay, so let's listen to
our dialogue one more time
And then we're gonna come back and Eric
is gonna tell us how much she hates Matt
All right children. Let's review Tommy
pay attention. Sorry, Miss Cadillac
Okay, Crystal now tell
me what's for plus 11
15 Miss Cadillac always as crystal.
She's such a teacher's pet
Okay, and what about 56 minus 60?
Um negative four very good 12
times 12 very good suck up 144
Zero divided by one zero.
How did you know that?
Okay, smarty pants
the square root of two
Bet you're not going
to get that one do it all
um 1.4 1.4 2.1 divide
All right, so Erika you were telling me
that you hated math or you still do well
Yes, that's I really do hate math
and even even doing a simple
You know like 16 plus 32 is too hard for me
So you were never really
that type of person that's
good with numbers No,
I'm terrible with numbers.
I can't even remember my own
phone number. Really. That's true
Like I really if someone asks me for my
phone number, I have to look on my phone
In the address book to find it
Well, yeah, sometimes
numbers can be difficult.
I kind of liked math when I
was younger. It's just made sense
Well, I guess there's a reason why I'm
an English teacher and I'm a math teacher
And I was actually not very
good at language, but here you
are exactly well. I mean in
Spanish. I had like grammar
Not very good at
that all those rules.
Yeah, but you're pretty good
at English. Oh, that's all right
That's all right. Yeah, what
about you guys tell us what your
favorite subject or your least
favorite subject in school was
What about you? Do you
have any favorite subject?
Don't did you have a favorite
subject? Um history history. Yeah, okay
I liked chemistry for a while. Oh, God
Involves numbers Well a little
bit, but it was interesting as well
So come to the website
everyone EnglishPod.
com and you can find
lots of other resources there
and also be sure to check out our
activity stream where you can answer and
Ask very quick questions
depending on your level
so you can choose if
you're an elementary student
Then you would be talking to
other elementarys. That's right.
Well, thanks for downloading
this lesson and until next time
Goodbye